getdroidtips.com 2019-06-23

# Privacy Policy

_Effective May 25, 2018_

We respect privacy and your rights to control your personal data. Our principle guidelines are simple. We will be clear about the data we collect and why. We may also change this Policy from time to time so please check this page occasionally to ensure that you’re happy with any changes. By using our website, you’re agreeing to be bound by this Policy and the [Terms of Use](https://www.getdroidtips.com/terms-of-use/).

This Privacy Policy (“ **Privacy Policy** ”) relates to the website www.getdroidtips.com (hereinafter referred to as the “ **Site** ”), the owner of the Site, (“ **We** “, “ **Us** “, “ **Our** “, “ **Ourselves** ” and/or “ **GetDroidTips”** ) and any related software applications (‘Apps’), where Personal Data is processed by the same (via the Site, any of Our Apps or otherwise) relating to You. In this Privacy Policy, “ **You** ” and “ **Your** ” and “ **User** ” refer to an identified or identifiable natural person being the User of the Site and/or any of Our provided services. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, our collection practices the processing of user information, or if you would like to report a security violation to us directly, please contact us via our [Contact Us page](https://www.getdroidtips.com/contact-us/) or our postal address (Mentioned below).

## 1\. Who we are

Our website address is https://www.getdroidtips.com, which is owned and managed by Mr. Abdul Razak.

## 2\. How do we collect information from you?

We collect information about you when you use our website, post comments or if you register to receive one of our weekly newsletters.

## 3\. What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### General Data

The use of our services will automatically create information that will be collected. For example, when you use our Services, how you use the Services, information about the type of device you use, your Open Device Identification Number, date/time stamps for your visit, your unique device identifier, your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address, and domain name are all collected. This information is used on our Site for the following purposes:

  * Operate, maintain, and improve our site and services;
  * Respond to comments and questions posted by you;
  * Send information including confirmations, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * Communicate about promotions, upcoming events, and other news about products and services offered by us and our selected partners;
  * Develop, improve, and deliver marketing and advertising for the Services;
  * Provide and deliver products and services you request;
  * Identify you as a user in our system;
  * Facilitate the creation of and secure your Account on our network.

### Log Files

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes IP addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (“ISP”), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to maintain and improve the performance of the Services.

### Cookies

“Cookies” are small pieces of information (text files) that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing the website. These text files that can be used by websites to make a user’s experience more efficient.

The law states that we can store these cookies on your device if they are strictly necessary for the operation of this site.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year. We also use third-party advertising companies (Google Adsense) to serve ads when you visit our Site, and they may deploy cookies in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

For more information on how to set your browser cookie restrictions, please refer to your browsers help function. Please be aware that restricting cookies could seriously restrict the functionality of our website.

###  **Analytics**

We use analytics services (Google Analytics) to help analyze how users use the Site. Google Analytics uses Cookies to collect information such as how often users visit the Site and we use the information to improve our Site and Services. The data we collect will be processed anonymously and “Data sharing” is disabled.

Google Analytics’ ability to use and share information collected by them is restricted by their terms of use and privacy policy, which you should refer to for more information about how these entities use this information. In order to be compliant with the new regulation, Google included a [data processing amendment](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/dpa/dataprocessingamendment_20130906.html). You can also visit [Google Analytics’ Help Page](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) to learn how it uses your data and commits to protecting it.

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form (such as the user’s name and email address), and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection (Using  _Akismet: Check Akismet[Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/) here_)

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available [here](https://automattic.com/privacy/).

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to this Site can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

Please visit their websites to learn more about how they collect your data.

###  **Advertising**

Ads appearing on our site are delivered to the Users by our advertising partner –  _Google Adsense_ , who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non-personal identification information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to our website or other websites. Google’s use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to our site and/or other sites on the Internet.

You may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). (Alternatively, you can also opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).) We are in compliant with GDPR Privacy Policy rules updated by Google and their products [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

## 

4\. Who we share your data with

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users’ personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes such as personalized ads, comments, newsletters, and others are outlined above.

We may use third-party service providers to help us operate our business and the Site or administer activities on our behalf, such as sending out newsletters or surveys. We may share your information with these third parties for those limited purposes provided that you have given us your permission.

## 

5\. Where we send your data

As outlined above, GetDroidTips.com.com may share the collected data with the following third-party networks and services:

  *  **Google and their partners**  – Please refer to [Google’s privacy policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/).
  *  **Akismet Anti-Spam**  – If you leave a comment on the site, Akismet may collect the required information for automated spam detection. Please visit their [privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/) to know more.
  *  **Push Engage –** If you subscribe to our push notification service, this will only collect the geolocation that is country, state, and the city at the time of subscription. This service does not store any personal data that can identify a subscriber individually at the time of web push subscription. In case if you don’t want to share your location, then you can disable it by navigating to Settings > Privacy settings. From there you can enable or disable the geolocation. Visit their [Privacy Policy](https://www.pushengage.com/privacy).
  *  **Cloudways**  – Cloudways is a cloud application deployment, management, and infrastructure management provider. Cloudways is providing us with managed Google Cloud Platform services. Please [Cloudways privacy policy](https://www.cloudways.com/en/terms.php#privacy) here.
  *  **Google Cloud Platform** – We are using the Google cloud server to store our content and data. Visit their [Privacy Policy page](https://policies.google.com/privacy) to know how they protect our content and data stored on their servers.

## 

6\. How long we retain your data

GetDroidTips.com strictly protects the security of your personal information and honors your choices for its intended use. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymize it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue. Information collected using Google Analytics is retained for a period of 14 months. After the end of the retention period, the data is deleted automatically.

## 

7\. How we protect your data

We strictly protect the security of your personal information and honor your choices for its intended use. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

  * We keep our software up to date and take a regular audit to improve security.
  * We use 2048 bit SSL certificate with modern TLS for the encryption.
  * We use the highly strong password and Two Factor Authentication everywhere.
  * We are also using security measures provided by CloudFlare to protect the Site. [Check Cloudflare Privacy Policy [Here](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/)]

## 

8. What data breach procedures we have in place?

  * We will notify you via email within 1 business day
  * We will notify the users via in-site notification within 1 business day
  * We also agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law. This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or government agencies to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

We believe you should have choices about the collection, use, and sharing of your information. Although you cannot opt-out of all data collection when you visit our sites, you can limit the collection, use, and sharing of your personally identifiable information. For information regarding your choices related to interest-based advertising, please refer to “Advertising” subsection under  “What personal data we collect and why we collect it” section above.
